#### GLOBAL PRODUCT MANAGER

**Executive Summary** 

Accomplished business development specialist, with extensive experience in acquisition strategy development, engineering management, new technology concepts, product engineering, and manufacturing engineering. Experienced in analyzing multiple inputs - market data, industry trends, and customer and competitor strategies - and turning them into concise recommendations that result in global business opportunities and growth.

# Core Qualifications

- Market and industry analyses
- Strategic planning
- Cross-functional team management
- Complex problem solving
- Business planning and development
- Project planning and management
- Product concepting and development

# Professional Experience

03/2014 to Current

Global Product Manager Danaher i1/4 Bartlesville, OK

- Providing global leadership for interior door panels, including technology road maps, product and process transfer recommendations, technical expertise, global information exchange, and detailed business acquisition strategies.
- Building acquisition strategies for global programs technology and manufacturing recommendations, competitive assessments, and pre RFQ activities.
- Establishing global interior expert teams to help facilitate cross business unit communication, enabling improved products and processes.

### 08/2006 to 02/2014

Business Development Manager Pega (Pegasystems Inc.) i1/4 CA, State

- Provided support for short and long term business development activities including mergers and acquisitions, new technology and process
  assessments and direction setting, customer and competitor assessments, business quoting, and long term business direction planning.
- Results of the business development activities included over \$250M of new interiors contracts.

#### 02/2004 to 07/2006

Applications Engineer Parker-Hannifin, Corporation i1/4 Shelby, NC

- Provided technical direction for new business opportunities, using marketing, government requirements, and customer requests as the basis.
- Initiated industrial design work, competitive vehicle benchmarks, warranty analyses, and lessons learned to help establish direction and plans for new business opportunities.
- Supported customer technology shows, including advanced planning, technology recommendations, and on site/face-to-face customer interfaces.

### 10/1999 to 01/2004

Advanced Engineering Manager Eaton Corporation il/4 Nashville, TN

- Established and managed new technology developments (including mechanical, electrical, material, and process types) for automotive interior commodities, starting with initial concepts and continuing through demonstration properties.
- Efforts led to over 15 patent disclosures and 1 issued patent.
- Coordinated global new development expert teams to ensure worldwide exchange of new product concepts and ideas.
- Managed team of advanced engineers and designers.

### 01/1999 to 09/1999

Project Manager Magellan Health Services il/4 Remote, VA

• Provided technical and purchasing direction for cockpit and console sub assemblies; initiated concepts, established feasibility, and led global activities to establish design, manufacturing, and craftsmanship direction for these commodities.

## 04/1997 to 12/1998

Systems Engineering Manager/Instrument Panel Engineering Manager Kord Technologies i1/4 Washington, DC

- Provided management and technical direction, including resource planning, technical budgets, and process establishment for the Detroit
  product engineering team.
- Enhanced links between the tier two supply base and the internal engineering groups.
- Worked with an outside consulting firm to improve product development efficiency.

# 06/1994 to 03/1997

Systems Engineer Intel Corp. il/4 Stamford, CT

Provided overall technical direction and product engineering management for multiple interior programs.

03/1992 to 05/1994

## Product Engineer Control Tec il/4 Ann Arbor, MI

• Coordinated product design and development for several automotive interior sub assemblies and components, and provided an interface to both the customer and manufacturing divisions.

## 06/1991 to 02/1992

Tool Engineer UT Automotive i1/4 City, STATE

 Coordinated primary and secondary tooling needed to produce automotive interior commodities, with focus on feasibility, supplier coordination, and sample part builds.

## Accomplishments

## People Management:

• Consistently received high ratings/feedback from direct reports about management style - regardless of their position or function.

# Financial Management:

• Have extensive knowledge of product pricing and financial metrics - gained over many years of quoting and competitive financial analyses. Experiences now result in strong understanding of how to competitively quote and win profitable business.

### Skills

- Advanced (20 years+): strategic and business planning, product development, complex problem solving, interior product acquisition development and quoting
- Extensive (15 years+): product and technology concepting, market and industry analyses
- Intermediate (7 years+): cross functional team leadership, employee management, advanced technology development, merger and acquisition support (strategy, analyses, and due diligence)

## Education

Bachelor of Science (BS): Mechanical Engineering GMI Engineering and Management Institute 11/4 City, State, USA